Simon Rose

Software Engineer

simon-rose.co.uk

Sheffield, UK



+447791863017

Profile

I am an ambitious and driven Software Engineer, experienced in designing and developing a range of web applications from web-based games to enterprise-level systems. I have a PhD in Computer Science and 7 years of professional software development experience, across both industry and academia. I have strong interpersonal and teaching skills and exceptional ability in organisation, planning and time management.

Experience

Associate Lecturer - Sheffield Hallam University

Oct 2016 - Present

- Preparing and delivering teaching content on a number of undergraduate Computer Science and Software Engineering modules.
- Supervising MSc, BSc and BEng students on their final year projects.
- End Point Assessor for the Digital and Technology Solutions Specialist MSc course.
- Student voice 'outstanding' member of staff 2016-17 and 2019-20.

Computing Teacher - Mercia Secondary School

Jan 2019 - July 2019

- Preparing and teaching content in-line with the computing national curriculum.

Founder - Simon Rose Software Development

Feb 2013 - Present

- Design and development of full stack web applications, primarily in JavaScript using frontend frameworks (AngularJS, Vue.js and React).
- Client liason and task management.

Full Stack Software Engineer - 3Squared

Sept 2013 - May 2016

- Developing bespoke web applications in C# using ASP.NET MVC and Web Forms.
- Working with a variety of web technologies including HTML, JavaScript and CSS.
- Application deployment using IIS.
- Version control using Git and Team Foundation Server.
- API design and implementation.
- Time estimations and risk reviews.

Education

PhD in Computer Science - Sheffield Hallam University

Oct 2016 - Sept 2019

Title: Developing Children's Computational Thinking Skills using Programming Games

Supervisors: Dr Jacob Habgood and Dr Tim Jay

Published work in academic journals and presented at several conferences during the PhD.

MComp Software Engineering - Sheffield Hallam University First Class (Honours)

Sept 2011 - July 2016

Award Classification Mark: 86.55%

Skills

Programming Languages	Frameworks/Software	Other Skills
- JavaScript (and TypeScript)	- Node.js	- Organised
- C#	- Angular	- Motivated
- C++	- Vue.js (and Vuex)	- Pragmatic
- Java	 React (and Redux) 	- Adaptable
- SQL	- Jest/Cypress	- Able to lead
- PHP	NET	- Business awareness
- HTML	- MongoDB	- Widely-read
- CSS (LESS and SASS)	- Photoshop	 Teaching/presenting
	- InDesign	

Projects

Cognitive Function Task May 2020 - Aug 2020

- An application that allows researchers to flexibly develop or customise cognitive function task assessments.
- Split into three parts: a CMS for managing tasks, an progressive web application for running tasks and a REST API that handles data.
- Developed using Vue.js for the front-end and Node.js for the back-end.
- Research project for the Centre of Mathematical Cognition at Loughborough University.

Pirate Plunder Sept 2017 - July 2018

- Educational block-based programming game.
- Teaches children how and why to use procedures in a Scratch-based language.
- MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack.
- Developed as part of my PhD.

Speakeasy Jan 2016 - May 2016

- Lead programmer in a team of 3.
- Augmentative and alternative communication speech generation software designed for children with cerebral palsy.
- Uses semantic compaction to combine chosen words to form more complex sentences.
- MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack.

Interests

Sport

I enjoy playing and watching sport, primarily football and resistance work in the gym. I play 6-a-side football regularly.

Reading

I like to read widely, I am always striving to broaden my knowledge and understanding on a wide range of topics. I set myself the goal to read a book a week in 2016 and have continued to exceed this target each year.

Travel

I am a keen traveller and enjoy backpacking. I have travelled around South East Asia, South America, Japan and several European countries in the last few years.

References

Dr Jacob Habgood

Director of Education Partnerships Sumo Digital jhabgood@sumo-digital.com **Mr James Fox**

Commercial Director 3Squared james.fox@3squared.com